济南市二零二三年九年级学业水平考试。
A. 1. Let's enjoy the folk music.
听录音，从每组句子中选出一个你所听到的句子，每个句子读一遍。
2. She likes paper cutting.
3. Can you make dumplings?
4. Lucy didn't stay up late.
5. How was the school trip?
B.,B Alex, where is your mom?
在录音中，你将听到五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从每小题中。中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。每段对话读两遍。六。
7. Do you often do sports,
Jack? Yes, almost every day.
Ping is my favorite.
8. Hi, Tony.
What did you do last night?
9. I watched a movie.
It was really funny.
9. can I go out for a walk?
10. Remember to take an umbrella.
It's raining outside.
10. What's the matter with
11. I have a toothache.
Take this medicine twice a day, and you will feel better soon.
13. I will.
Thanks. C.,B 15.
在录音中，你将听到一段对话。二对话后有五个小题，从每小题中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。听对话前，你将有四十秒钟的读题时间；听完后，你将有四十秒钟的答题时间。对话读两遍。
Hey, Bob. What did you do last summer vacation?
16. I went to Chengdu to see the lovely pandas with my friends.
It was an exciting trip.
How about you, Jenny?
I volunteered in a hospital to cheer up the sick kids with my sister.
18. And how did you come up with this idea?
19. I want to be a doctor when I grow up.
Volunteering there can help me learn more about the job.
20. I remember you dreamed to be a dancer before.
21. Yes, but I have changed my dream.
22. Really? Why?
23. In the past three years, I've seen many doctors save lives without thinking
about themselves. And I hope to be like them.
24. It's really nice of you.
What will you do for your dream?
25. I am going to study medicine at a university in the future.
26. That sounds great.
I think you'll be a good doctor.
Hey, Bob. What did you do last summer vacation?
I went to Chengdu to see the lovely pandas with my friends.
It was an exciting trip.
How about you, Jenny?
28. I volunteered in a hospital to cheer up the sick kids with my sister.
Wonderful! And how did you come up with this idea?
I want to be a doctor when I grow up.
Volunteering there can help me learn more about the job.
30. I remember you dreamed to be a dancer before.
21. Yes, but I have changed my dream.
Really? Why? 22.
In the past three years, I've seen many doctors save lives without thinking about
themselves. And I hope to be like them.
It's really nice of you.
What will you do for your dream?
I am going to study medicine at a university in the future.
That sounds great.
I think you'll be a good doctor.
30. Thank you listening.
在录音中，你将听到一篇短文。短文后有五个小题，从每小题中选出能回答所给问题的正确答案。听短文前，你将有。四十秒钟的读题时间，听完后你将有四十秒钟的答题时间。短文读两遍。
Thank you for listening.
I've loved animals since I was a little girl, but my parents are busy at work all
day and I'm at school until 5 p.m.
This is why every time I asked to get a pet, they said no.
Things changed on a rainy day a few years ago.
I was coming back from school with my best friend when we saw a rubbish bin move.
There was a black bag inside and when she took it out and opened it, I saw a little
dog. I think it was less than a month old because some of its teeth were still
missing. The dog looked sad and hungry, so I took it home.
While I was waiting for my parents to get back, I gave the dog some meat and water.
The dog drank the whole bowl of water, but it didn't eat anything.
Then it lay down on the carpet in the living room and slept.
When my parents got home, they were surprised.
My father sat down on the sofa and the dog jumped onto his legs.
Tina, how cute the dog is.
Dad smiled and said, touching its head.
My mother went into the kitchen and came back with some meat.
This time the dog ate it.
Then she asked me to choose a name for it.
She also said if I wanted to keep the dog, I would have to look after it every day.
We have had Lucky for four years now.
She's part of my family and we all love her.
I've loved animals since I was a little girl, but my parents are busy at work all
day and I'm at school until 5 p.m.
This is why every time I asked to get a pet, they said no.
Things changed on a rainy day a few years ago.
I was coming back from school with my best friend when we saw a rubbish bin move.
There was a black bag inside and when she took it out and opened it, I saw a little
dog. I think it was less than a month old because some of its teeth were still
missing. The dog looked sad and hungry, so I took it home.
While I was waiting for my parents to get back, I gave the dog some meat and water.
The dog drank the whole bowl of water, but it didn't eat anything.
Then it lay down on the carpet in the living room and slept.
When my parents got home, they were surprised.
My father sat down on the sofa and the dog jumped onto his legs.
Tina, how cute the dog is.
Dad smiled and said, touching its head.
My mother went into the kitchen and came back with some meat.
This time the dog ate it.
Then she asked me to choose a name for it.
She also said if I wanted to keep the dog, would have to look after it every day.
We have had Lucky for four years now.
She's part of my family and we all love her.